# Mansoor Nabawi

Marienburgerstr. 72, 31141 Hildesheim 0157 35560393

mansoor.nabawi@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/mansoor-nabawi github.com/Mansoorinho

With a master's degree in Data Analytics from Universität Hildesheim and a rich background spanning academia, Bosch, and startups, I bring expertise in Data Science, Machine Learning, and Deep Learning.

#### Skills

- Machine Learning
- Deep Learning
- Computer Vision
- Data Analysis
- Data Visualization
- Python, C++, Bash
- PostgreSQL, SQL
- Pytorch, OpenCV
- Natural Language Processing
- Time Series Analysis

- AWS, Google Colab
- Apache Hadoop, Spark
- GitHub Actions, Jira, Confluence
- Numpy, Pandas, Scikit-learn, Scipy
- Matplotlib, Plotly, Flask, Dash

# **Experience**

AUG 2023 -FEB 2024 **Master's Thesis Student** 

(Masterand)

**Robert Bosch GmbH** 

Hildesheim, Germany

DEC 2022 -JUL 2023 **Working Student Evaluation of** 

**Automated Driving Assistance** 

Robert Bosch GmbH Hildesheim, Germany

DEC 2021 -AUG 2022 **Working Student Data Science** 

acto GmbH (formerly insightsON)

Paderborn, Germany

- Developed novel approaches for 2.5D Vehicle Detection with L-shape polygons.
- Created a 2.5D dataset from 3D KITTI dataset.
- Proposed new evaluation metrics for the 2.5D Vehicle Detection.
- · Created dashboards and visualizations.
- Analyzed prediction results and Computer Vision tasks.
- Data preprocessing, quality check, feature engineering.
- Improving churn prediction by 20% using ensembles, boosting and stacking techniques, and finding churn reasons using segmentation and customer journey mapping.
- Performing Seasonality Detection and finding periods in which clients have seasonal effects instead of churning.
- Proposing new ideas on solving problems.
- Active participation in meetings to further develop the business strategy of the startup.

OCT 2021 -NOV 2021

**Student Assistant Data Analytics** 

Stiftungsuniversität Hildesheim

Hildesheim, Germany

- Helping with class organization and answering students' questions regarding the class materials.
- Reading and implementing scientific papers.

JAN 2019 - Chief Operating Officer & Co-JUL 2020 Founder

Retina Corps
Tehran, Iran

FEB 2018 - Freelance Web Designer

FEB 2019 Retina Corps

Tehran, Iran

• Responsible for managing a team of six employees in a digital marketing startup.

 Helping employees to gain the right knowledge and information.

• Designed websites using WordPress, HTML and CSS.

#### **Education**

OCT 2020 - MSc. in Data Analytics /

Universität Hildesheim

Hildesheim, Germany

• M.Sc. Thesis: 2.5D Vehicle Detection with L-shape Polygon. Thesis grade: 1.3

• Student Research Project: Art pieces from GANs, reaching 1st place in a Kaggle challenge.

• Important coursework: NLP, Time Series, Planning and Optimal Control, Survey Sampling, Machine Learning, Advanced Machine Learning, Big Data Analytics, Modern Optimization Techniques, Distributed Data Analytics.

SEP 2015 - BSc. in Computer Engineering-FEB 2020 Software

> IAU-TNB Tehran, Iran

• B.Sc. Thesis: Online movie recommender system using Apache Spark. Thesis Grade: 1.0

• Important coursework: Advanced Programming, Data Structure, Database, Software Engineering, Artificial Intelligence and Intelligent Systems, Software Testing, Computer Networks, Object-oriented System Design.

## **Certificates**

- Introduction to TensorFlow for AI, Machine Learning, and Deep Learning. Coursera 12/2021.
- Machine Learning, Stanford University. Offered through Coursera 12/2019.
- IBM Data Science Professional Certificate. Coursera 10/2019.
- Big Data. Jahad-e-Daneshgahi Sharif 08/2019.

### **Honors & Awards**

- Landesstipendium Niedersachsen from 10/2023 until 03/2024.
- Deutschlandstipendium from 10/2021 until 10/2023.

#### References

- Alexander Lengsfeld, Robert Bosch GmbH, alexander.lengsfeld@de.bosch.com
- Muhammad Abdur Rafae, Universität Hildesheim, rafaem@uni-hildesheim.de
- Andre Stolhans, acto GmbH: 0152 09101309